<dashboard version="1.1" stylesheet="help_using.css">
  <label>Using the Template for Citrix XenDesktop</label>
  
  <row>
    <html>

<h1>Alerts</h1>
<h2>Alert Searches</h2>
<p>
  Alerts are saved searches that look for anomalies in your machine data.  To view these alert searches, click "Settings" -> "Searches and reports", or <a href="/manager/TemplateForXenDesktop7/saved/searches">follow this link</a>. <br/>
</p>
<p>
  Alert searches begin with the word "Alert -"
</p>
<p>
  These saved searches can be modified, disabled, or removed.  Additionally, new searches can be created to look for specific situations to meet your needs.  More information about alerting in Splunk
  <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Alert" target="_blank">can be found here</a>.
</p>

<h2>Adjusting Alert Thresholds</h2>
<p>
  Alert thresholds are defined as <code>macros</code>.  The values for the alert thresholds can be <a href="/manager/TemplateForXenDesktop7/admin/macros">modified here.</a>
</p>

<p>
  To modify by hand, read the documentation on <code>macros.conf</code> here -> <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Admin/Macrosconf" target="_blank">http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Admin/Macrosconf</a>
</p>

<h2>Setting up Email Alerts</h2>
<p>
  Email server settings can be <a href="/manager/TemplateForXenDesktop7/admin/alert_actions/email?action=edit">specified here.</a>
</p>

<p>
  Alert action setting documentation can be found here -> <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Alert/SetUpAlertActions" target="_blank">http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Alert/SetUpAlertActions</a>
</p>


<h1>Windows Event Log Tuning</h1>
<p>
  By default, the TA-XD7-VDA add-on located on the Splunk Universal Forwarders installed on the XenDesktop machines collect events from the following Windows Event Logs:
  <ul>
    <li>Application - Event Ids 1000-1011.  This limits collection to application crashes or hangs.</li>
    <li>System - all events.</li>
    <li>Security - all events.</li>
    <li>Setup - all events.</li>
    <li>Microsoft/Windows/GroupPolicy/Operational - all events.  See the section below about GPO logging.</li>
  </ul>
</p>
<p>
  To tune which event logs and events the Universal Forwarder gathers, modify <code>inputs.conf</code> on the Universal Forwarders as specified in the Splunk documentation here ->
  <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Data/Monitorwindowsdata" target="_blank">http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Data/Monitorwindowsdata</a>
</p>

<h1>Lookup Files</h1>

<h2>Generated Lookup Files</h2>
<p>
  Several dashboards use coma separated value (CSV) lookup files.
  For example, a lookup file called winHosts.csv contains information about hosts including Operating Systems, installed memory, core count, etc.
  These lookup files are modified saved searches that run on a periodic basis.  To view these lookup file builders, click "Settings" -> "Searches and reports",
  or <a href="/manager/TemplateForXenDesktop7/saved/searches">follow this link.</a>
</p>

<p>
  Lookup builder searches begin with the words <strong>"Lookup -"</strong>
</p>

<h2>Static Lookup Files</h2>
<p>
  In addition to the generated lookup files, several static lookup files are included.  These files contain information like Citrix device platform types.  These files may need to be manually modified if new information becomes available from the manufacturer.
</p>

<h1>GPO Logging</h1>
<p>
  The Universal Forwarders use PowerShell to gather information from the Windows Event Log about Group Policy Processing events.
  More information about this technique can be found in this blog article -> <a href="http://blogs.splunk.com/2014/02/05/measuring-windows-group-policy-logon-performance/" target="_blank">http://blogs.splunk.com/2014/02/05/measuring-windows-group-policy-logon-performance/</a>
</p>

<h1>Troubleshooting</h1>
<p>
  <table>
    <th>Problem</th>
    <th>Possible Solution</th>
    
    <tr>
      <td>No data on any dashboards.</td>
      <td>
	<ul>
	  <li>Ensure <a href="/manager/TemplateForXenDesktop7/data/inputs/tcp/cooked">receiving is enabled</a>.</li>
	  <li>Make sure firewalls are not blocking your receiving port (9997 by default).</li>
	  <li>Check the <code>splunkd.log</code> file located on your XenDesktop machines.  By default, <coce>splunkd.log</coce> is located in <code>C:\Program Files\SplunkUniversalForwarder\var\log\splunk</code></li>
	</ul>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>Only performance data is displayed.  No session, site, application, etc. data is displayed.</td>
      <td>
	Most likely, the PowerShell ExecutionPolicy has not been set to RemoteSigned.  Refer to the <a href="https://github.com/splunk/splunk-template-xendesktop-7/blob/master/app/TemplateForXenDesktop7/Installation.pdf" target="_blank">installation instructions</a> for further information.
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>No sites populated in the Site drop down list.</td>
      <td>
	<a href="/app/TemplateForXenDesktop7/help_rebuild_site_lookup">Rebuild the site lookup file.</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>No data on server performance dashboards.</td>
      <td>
	<a href="/app/TemplateForXenDesktop7/help_rebuild_host_farm_lookup">Rebuild the host to farm lookup file.</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>No data for processor queue length.</td>
      <td>
	The statistics for processor queue length are calculated based on the number of cores in the system.  The number of cores is stored in a lookup file called <code>winHosts.csv</code>.
	<a href="/app/TemplateForXenDesktop7/help_rebuild_winHosts_lookup">Rebuild the Windows host lookup file.</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>No data for memory usage.</td>
      <td>
	The statistics for memory usage are calculated based on the memory used as well as the total amount of system memory.  The amount of system memory is stored in a file called <code>winHosts.csv</code>.
	<a href="/app/TemplateForXenDesktop7/help_rebuild_winHosts_lookup">Rebuild the Windows host lookup file.</a>
      </td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>Unexpected or no data on the usage calendar.</td>
      <td>
	The usage calendar uses a lookup file called <code>calendar_users.csv</code>.  A scheduled saved search populates the statistics on this calendar.  You can manually run this search or use the
	<a href="/app/TemplateForXenDesktop7/help_update_calendar_usage">Update Calendar Usage Data</a> form.
      </td>
    </tr>
    
  </table>
</p>



    </html>
  </row>
 
  
</dashboard>
